Why? You know, so the feedback I got was
that she told me that I should put
in the email.
>> Eating Vietnamese food doesn't make you
ready to work in Vietnam.
>> Definitely um did face certain culture
shocks and culture gaps.
>> My style was very straightforward and
they thought that I was a very mean
person.
>> Without HR making that flexibility, I
wouldn't even be here today. personally
drove me to some point of exhaustion
where I didn't want to repeat that cycle
again and again.
>> You said around 3 we order coffee or
gesture, right?
>> 3 p.m. is a snack time.
>> First of all, I would like to welcome
all of you to our series content brought
to you by Predential Vietnam Assurance.
My name is Ling, host of the series. In
the podcast, first of all, we would like
to interview our leader manager and also
financial expert in the insurance
industry through those conversation. I
hope that you guys the audience can have
the different perspective especially on
the changings now day. The topic today
will be the story of the two Vietnamese
returning overseas and how they choosing
potential and secondly is their journey
of jump into the different industries.
It is their bonus of courage. And today
I would like to invite our two special
guests and Chris Cow the head of IT risk
and also fun to head of PD business
planning
and uh may you introduce a bit about
yourself.
>> So hello everyone uh my name is Tai and
I'm currently the head of PD business
planning with Credential Vietnam
assurance.
>> Hello everyone. So my name is
Christopher Cao. I'm currently the head
of IT risk at Credential Vietnam.
>> Okay. So um maybe you can introduce a
bit about yourself before joining
Predential.
So before joining PVA um I was actually
studying in the States. So I was born in
Ho Chi Min City. I came to the States
when I was 10 years old. So I grew up
there. I went to um UCLA, majored in
business economics and accounting. So in
2019 um after I graduated I decided to
come back home and um find a place with
credential as a management traininee at
that time.
>> So for myself um so I born in France uh
in a city named Rojimo it's just nearby
Paris in the suburb of Paris and I I
grew up and I spent more than 30 years
of my life uh in France. So I major in
uh audit and finance in a business
school but during my studies I I I
develop interest for information
technology. So that's where when I
started my career in 2010 I I start my
career in a in a audit and consulting
firm specializ in IT audit and IT
advisory.
>> Okay. So actually I see that and and
Chris you came back from France and we
came back from the state. I would say
like American dream people would like to
study abroad comes abroad especially
like France or like America why you
choose to come back to Vietnam. Well, I
think deciding where to live is actually
up to the person, right? So, for me
individually, I just like the vibe in Ho
Chi Min. And um with all of my families
um still in Vietnam, I just wanted to
return home after I finished my my
studies. And part of the reason another
reason why I wanted to um return to
Vietnam was basically the career
opportunities in a developing market. I
feel that um I will be able to pursue
countless opportunities if I'm were to
return home. So that's the reason why I
decided to come back.
>> How about you?
>> So for myself, I always wanted to work
in Asia back then when I was a student.
So that's why I took every single
opportunity to move abroad. So when I
was still a student, I I I I studied in
um six months in Shanghai, China. I did
some internships in Hanoi, Ho Chima
city. That's where I start to get my
network in Vietnam back then 2008. I did
some internship in India as well, but I
graduated in 2009. So back then it was
the global financial crisis. So
extremely hard to find a job and even
harder to find a job abroad, right? So I
still managed to land a job in
consulting in my hometown N in in France
but in the back of my mind I always
wanted to at some point to go to Asia. I
love the excitement of you know like uh
the the environment of working in Asia.
Um but why Vietnam specifically? Uh I
have this connection with Vietnam
because my parents are are Vietnamese
even though I born and grew up in
France. Actually I say that I returned
to Vietnam. So it was also uh due p due
to personal reason because um I wanted
my mother to come with me and uh Vietnam
was the best choice obviously because
she would feel at home in Vietnam.
>> Okay. So um may I ask what is the
trigger point when you made your
decision
like the emotional trigger here and then
you say that okay this is time for me to
back home. this is time for me to jump
into another different industry. This is
a time when I want to work for this
company. So um emotions have always been
a part of the whole decision building
up. It's not like a trigger point
because I don't make my decision based
on one emotion but emotion has always
been something in the back of my mind as
I prepare to move. But I think the
trigger point here is when I found an
opportunity with PBA because back then
like I was just moving back at 22 years
old not having a network in Vietnam
existing network but um receiving the
career offer to join PVA was actually
that trigger point. And I think when I
got that offer it made my parents more
confident that they allow me to or not
allow me but they it made them feel more
confident that you know I return home to
start my career here. Yes, as you know,
I as I mentioned before, I've been
working 14 years in consulting, which is
a significant amount of time in this
particular uh industry.
And um at some point I was seeing that
year after year it was repetitive.
That's one thing. And I I don't like
repetition. It's always the same cycle,
the same fiscal year, the same goals,
the same KPIs. And most to be more
specific about what I was doing before
right at intering you have also a
pressure on the numbers like you need to
do KPIs you need to do utilization every
day you need to logging your time sheet
so you need to justify like like from
Monday to Friday how many hours you
spend on proposals how many hours you
spend on business development how many
hours you spend on project A B C and
that personally drove me to some point
of exhaustion
right where I didn't want to repeat that
cycle again and again. That's the first
thing. Second thing, there is also this
frustration of going at the surface only
when you advise client, right? Because
you have not only one client, you have
many, right? And your scope of work is
only what is in the contract, right? So
once you deliver the the project, the
implementation most of the time is done
by the internal team, by the clients. So
you don't see the real impact on the
day-to-day of what you're advising or
recommending to the clients. So I wanted
to to see what's on the other side,
right? And uh that drove me to to to
move to credential. I I had this
opportunity in uh 2024 this offer.
Actually my position is new. It's a new
position. Credential head of it. There
was no head of it before uh because
credential reached the critical size and
maturity and complexity that requires to
have this specific expertise and team to
ensure that we manage properly the
technology risk within the company and
for our customers
>> in Pa what is the difference of course
you have the KPI right so what I would
say is that um at PVA KPIs is not just
the what but there's also the how part
of it right so it's not like you hit 10
points out of 10 points then it's a KPI
achieved but it's like how you get there
so so what makes it different is that um
leaders don't just look at the final
outcome in terms of the quantitative
outcome but they also look at the best
efforts that um an employee puts in so I
think that's what that's what is
different to me in terms of KPI at PBA
>> for when you mentioned that you apply
for PBA even that when you are in stage.
How was that processed?
>> It was it was an actually it was
actually an interesting um process. So I
I knew PVA through a career post. I
think was on Facebook and then um I
applied and then I went through the
online interview round and also um the
game the game round, right? So when I
reached my last round of the selection
process, it was an assessment center
that requires you to be in person. But
the date of that um AC was when I was
still in the states. So I wasn't able to
fly home on time for that AC. So what I
did was like I actually emailed um the
HR person at that time with very little
hope that um they would reschedu for me
but they ended up supporting and they
ended up rescheduled to um the day that
after I landed in Vietnam. So I think
that's that's like the um the difference
point because without HR making that
flexibility I wouldn't even be here
today. when you back to Vietnam, have
you faced like the cultural shock in
terms of like the community, the
communication?
>> So, I definitely um did face certain
culture shocks and culture gaps. Even
though I identify myself as a
Vietnamese, I speak Vietnamese, but um
once entering a professional workforce,
things are just different, right? You
don't I talk in Vietnamese, but it's not
like a casual way of talking. Writing
emails, um how to greet a person who is
first of all older and more experienced.
Just very little things like that were
also um were already a shock to me in
term of the culture. And um as I shared
before, I I was fortunate to have the
exposure of two different cultures, the
American culture and the Vietnamese
culture. But what I had to do was to
find the right mix. So for example,
right? So I cannot be overly um a
pushover or overly assertive if that
situation requires me to be more like
yield or softer in terms of
communication. So the key is to find a
balance between Asian culture and
American culture and then adapt to the
PVA environment.
Can you share a specific example when
you have to face that culture shock?
>> Yeah, so um I was only in my second week
and I was assigned a task to chase or to
remind one of one of my colleague to um
send a document. Right? So I sent an
email very politely. It just say please
um be reminded that this is due today
and then best regards V. But what really
shocked me was I got a feedback saying
that I should be more uh like softer in
my communication. So I was like I don't
know how I was supposed to be soft when
I'm chasing someone who's late. So the
feedback I got was that she told me that
I should put
I was like, why? You know, but she just
told me it just makes people feel more
comfortable and less less offended when
they get chased. So So that was a very
um shocking example to me at that time.
>> Now, have you put any like nah into like
every email to trans people?
>> No, because it doesn't fit me. But I
changed the tone a little bit. So
instead of just make it really dry and
professional, I should put nah or like
just ah right but yeah it just doesn't
fit me.
>> Yeah.
>> And how about you? Have you ever faced
any like the culture shock?
>> Yes. Uh definitely. Um, so being
Vietnamese living in France, like just
speaking Vietnamese at home, eating
Vietnamese food doesn't make you ready
to walk in Vietnam. It's a totally
different story, right? Living and
especially walking here. Uh, I don't
know about the US working environment. I
just know about the I used to work in
France, right? But in France there is a
separation between uh professional and
personal a strict separation. Although
in Vietnam this separation is blur,
right? And and people tend to be more
emotional at work. Like for instance, uh
when I feed back to my team, sometimes
someone send me a document and I have
some comment that it needs to be
revised, it needs to be enhanced, then
the person might take it very
personally. Although I'm not commenting
on the person at all. It's nothing
personal at all. It's strict strictly
business. I'm just saying that this can
be done in another way, can be done
better. You need to enhance this, right?
But here um yeah, I I had to learn the
hard way that um people can take it
personally. So I noticed not in PVA but
in my previous consulting company in in
Vietnam that uh people start to be kind
of against me because I was too
straightforward. My style was very
straightforward and they thought that I
was a very mean person. Actually, I'm
not mean. It's just that uh it's only
work. I have nothing against the person
personally, but I I I just need the work
to get done the way I I need it to get
done. So that's the first thing, the
first cultural shock for me, like the
the more emotional. So I need to be more
careful about this. Um the second thing
is that when you work in Vietnam, from
my experience and my observation is that
doing well and quality is not enough.
You really need to build trust with the
people you are working with with the
stakeholders right again I think because
it's also personal so the people need to
feel that they can trust you so you need
to do the effort to build some
connections and some relationship with
the stakeholders that we are dealing
with either your clients or or within
the company right so that's also the
second thing that I I had to learn
because for me before when I was in
France as long as to execute well with
the quality then everyone is happy but
in Vietnam is not like that the the
personal inter inter relationship is
important everywhere but in Vietnam is
more important than than than what I've
seen before in in France
>> actually whenever I think about insulin
I think okay is dry stiff and this is
not really attractive so for you how you
assess this industry and how about the
other like Vietnamese returnees assessed
industry. Is this really attractive to
like the young people?
>> I would say the life insurance industry
in Vietnam is a very young market. I
mean the penetration rate is is not high
like it's what 10% of the population. So
it's like a it's like a growing um
industry and there's a lot of potential
for for young talents for experienced
professionals to to you know like even
advance the career within the insurance
industry in Vietnam. And there's a lot
of um moving parts. So the regulations
changed the whole industry crisis just
kind of reshaping the way that life
insurance works in Vietnam and all of
that would just be the perfect timing
for anyone especially young talents to
jumpstart their career.
Yes, that's true that from outside you
say insurance doesn't sound like the
most sexy industry in the world but
since I joined there's so many things
happening right uh first it's a complex
environment
um the regulations you mentioned before
it's complex and always changing and
evolution need to catch up with that um
for my part that I look at more
specifically is technology right so we
have a lot of transformation going on we
have very exciting exciting uh AI use
case that we already implemented and
implementing. So there are a lot of
dynamics going on. So I think it's not
just like um boring or not. It's not
just about the product itself or like
insurance products but it's also about
the people that we work with right so
first is the dynamic of the market of
Vietnam is extremely uh exciting
environment like fast growing a lot of
areas of growing for for prodial because
as you mentioned penetration rate is
still very low in Vietnam in the
meantime there is this commitment from
credential to transformation
and again in my in the domain I look
after technology There are a lot of
transformations going on. So actually
there are a lot of things to do. My team
is super busy. So it is very exciting.
It's nothing boring. Since I joined I
haven't haven't seen anything boring
about this industry at all.
>> Uh I see that when you back to Vietnam
and joining PBA at like very young age
uh and then you move up in the career
ladder as in the MT. So in your team we
ask like how many people in your team
what is your their what is their average
age? So currently in my team um around
10 10 people and um all of them are
older than me except one person is like
a year younger than me and um their
experience is is way more than than
mine. they have like up to 10 years of
experience with the industry.
>> Yeah.
>> So when you lead a team with like most
of the team members are older than you.
What is the challenge here and how you
overcome this challenge?
>> So when when I get the um opportunity to
transition to a new role within PD, I
definitely faced um a lot of pressure
and a a lot of challenges. Right. So
like you said in Vietnam leading someone
who is older and who is more experienced
or just leading in general I think it
requires trust and good communication.
So I would definitely imagine that one
of the challenge that I face once
someone here that I'm stepping into this
um head of department role would
definitely be doubts. That would be
number one thing. Doubt is definitely
like is she suitable for this? she
mature enough to lead a team of you know
like this many people and I feel like
once um I get that opportunity and I say
yes to that opportunity I believe that
both the company and I are taking some
risk on ourselves risk of me not
succeeding. Um and how I actually
overcome it is well I I always believe
that I need to earn trust from the
members and how I earn trust is just to
be very um genuine and be very
authentic. So when when it comes to the
new team I will not hide what I don't
know right I will ask if it's something
I don't know I will ask I will not
pretend like I'm a know-it-all because I
actually don't and I respect each of the
person in my team differently. I treat
them with respect, with care and I I
treat them with the experience that you
know they they they know more than I do.
So by building that trust and
relationships
um I'm by by doing that I feel like
leaders will be able to lead with their
team and also lead with influence. So
that's what I believe in and I'm still
working on that day to day.
>> In PVA any other tool or like supporting
system to help you overcome this for
example like uh while they working in
the bank they do have like anonymous
letter to your leader just for example
PVA there's um a lot of coaching and
mentoring opportunities. So HR um did
reach out to me and like ask me to
identify a mentor that I'm comfortable
with and they actually encouraged me to
you know like book frequent lunch or
catch up with them. And besides the
relationship meetings there's also a
leap program for for leadership.
Basically you go to like a two days
workshop hear from um experts and
actually bring it home and apply. But
what what has been working for me is I
learn um through observations. So I
learn through my past leaders. I I watch
them lead the team and I learn their
success but I also learn what they
didn't succeed in and I try to reflect
and apply that to myself.
But back to your case when you said that
you recruit like three people.
Yeah. how this criteria for you to
recruit a team member
>> on one hand is the technical expertise
right uh I need like for instance like
recently I just on boarded a senior
manager specialized in cyber security
data and privacy right so it's pretty
niche not not easy to find in uh in
Vietnam so
um one crit is the tech technical
parties the second one is the agile
mindset right? Continue to learn, be
able to to keep keep up to date with the
emerging technology, emerging threats.
And the third is to be able to uh be
good at stakeholder management because
in risk, not just technology, but risk
management in overall, you need to be
able to influence the stakeholders,
right? U so stakeholder management is
also one part which is quite heavy in in
our job. You cannot just be good
technically but if you don't know how to
communicate with people it doesn't work
or you if you just know how to
communicate with people but technically
you don't have the background doesn't
work neither.
>> Can you share like can you share a
concrete example when you have to manage
the manage the stakeholder by
communication. Okay. So to respond to
your question, uh stakeholder management
song. So uh the things you mentioned in
you work for the banking industry before
right and you said that usually the
teams are afraid of risk. Um I think in
terms of stakeholder management at at uh
at prudential
we
we are here to risk is there is this
misconception that risk is like uh
uh might slow down
some initiatives because you need to
have the green light from risk before
you implement some initiatives or go
live some systems right but we are not
here to slow down anything like we need
to change at pace rapidly.
uh I mentioned that digital
transformation all those new technology
initiatives needs to go at at pace
because we need to keep up and be
competitive. So definitely we cannot we
are not here to to to slow down but we
are here to master help the company and
the the stakeholders to to to master the
risk. So to ensure that look we do yes
we can do fast but we need to do it
right. we need to do it right
>> like if it's impossible then I would
need to play my role as the leader of
the team to in a way manage the
expectations of my boss and find a
solution maybe that extend that um
deadline by until tomorrow instead of
midnight today for for example but at
the same time managing up is one thing
but also managing peers and matching
down is another thing so I would I would
um explain the context to my team
members and so so that to help them
understand why there's a need for
change,
motivate them. What I actually learned
from my ex- boss, he's no longer here,
but what I really appreciated is that
once he get um the changes and he feels
that the team is not happy, he actually
texts us out for like snacks or coffee
even just have an hour half an hour
break in the workday and after we get
back like I myself and also my peers
feel more motivated and we we just we
just dive in. So that's what I learned
from one of my my bosses and I find that
to be a really really good way to
motivate and engage the team members and
actually get their hands-on support
>> because we need to protect our our
company obviously but most most
importantly is to protect our customers
right to ensure that our pro customer
like for instance the information like
is is well protected that's one example
so
in the way we communicate with the
stakeholders. I I I I try to you know
convey that message to show the value of
risk. So I'm I'm also like a kind of
internal advisor to raise the points
that maybe the team project teams
implementing a new system didn't think
of. So my team is here to make sure that
first we comply with all the security
requirements and we comply with all the
regulatory requirements but we also add
value but advising and to ensure that
you know they they they uh there are
some points that they are not missing.
Okay. So again we are not here to slow
down but in back to the stakeholder
managements it's important to remind
that in our in our communication
otherwise if I just send an email and I
say have you done ABC it doesn't work
right so we need to work closer with the
stakeholders and and make them
understand really like what's the
purpose of risk management why are we
doing this and what's the value
>> if I'm your friend asking hi Chris how
about the working space in Vietnam
I'm I'm also an expert in insurance.
Should I come to Vietnam and work?
>> Working in France back in for me back in
this was like like I was in the highway
like a very clear uh you know path but
also repetitive. It's like a cycle
repeating itself. And here is everything
is in the discovery mode. It's like a
big adventure. So this the dynamic of
the market of the developing country
right although credential has a long
history of Vietnam operating in Vietnam
for more than 25 years but it still need
to uh is still in transformation process
right since I joined a year ago so many
change happening so many change
happening so I said to my friend it's
very fun she is never boring there are
always things happening and u I would
say yeah the key word is for fun.
>> Let's say you are have a conversation
with a very young and then at very
beginning of their career like me. How
would you say to this young and then
very passionate in working environment
in PA?
>> Find a place where they value you and
they invest in people and credential is
definitely a place which invest heavily
in people.
like there are a lot of events for the
employees uh a lot of learning
um there's some program I think you were
part of that like the management
training program where doing one year
and a half two years two years when you
did some rotation across different
divisions so you get exposure in all
different aspects of uh of life
insurance right and that's also a boost
in the career like V I think is a a
testimony of that like uh She managed at
the very young age to to reach that that
position and I observed myself since
joining credentials that as long as you
are a talent
I mean as long as you are performing
well you will be recognized as a talent
regardless of your age or your
background your profile I've seen very
young people who are managing some
internal critical projects critical
initiatives and uh they are being
empowered with you know a lot of
responsibilities but very
So it doesn't matter. It's not like a
framework when you need to have x years
of experience before you move on to the
next steps. Here it's like okay we
recognize you if you're performing well
if you are tenant you will be recognized
as as such at credential.
So it leads a question to we actually as
I know the MT the management traininee
program not only happen in PBA we have
it in other company other industry what
is the difference here
>> now nowadays right a lot of um companies
actually have that whether it's a
management traininee or a fresh grat I
think banks have it to to attract young
talents but um what I think if if you
were about to decide decide which place
I should come to. Then look at the
culture of that place. I think for me I
like I like PVA and what I mean by
looking at the culture is like Chris
said right find a place that invests in
you. So what I would actually add on is
also find a place first of all that's
healthy that's invest in you allows you
to to learn to fail and then to redo it.
But another advice I would also give to
the young talents because I myself have
been through it is is personal
reflection. I feel like um in Vietnamese
they're saying that you know
right. So first of all um know who you
are and know what you want. You don't
have to know it like crystal clear but
at least have an idea of what you are
really looking for and be open-minded.
be courageous to to take risk and then
to fail and also just it's very
important to be humble because nowadays
I I feel like there's a tendency it's
very easy for for young graduates to
lose that humbleness and I feel like
being humble will get you very far.
>> Can you describe like a typical day
working in PVA?
>> A typical day usually so in the morning
I would have some daily standup meeting.
So we call that daily stand up. We were
not standing up. We're sitting on the
chair. We had Microsoft team but we just
call that it's agile
>> like you standing up and then
>> you can if it's a physical
>> meeting usually the principle is that
you are standing up for a short amount
of time 15 minutes
>> surely stand up.
>> So to the reason is to keep it short and
concise. Yeah.
>> So that's the reason we call that
standup meeting. I also not every day
but on the at least on a monthly basis I
will have like um individual catch up
with everyone of of my team member
actually I have open policy right they
can come to me anytime I'm very
accessible very they can come talk to me
anytime when there is a a concern an
issue whatever but I still want to have
this channel for them a official channel
for them so we can discuss one by one
and they can raise with me any concern
that they may have It's open. I allow
them to challenge me as well. So it's
like maybe they they they disagree with
my decision or maybe they want they they
have a different perception. So I want
them to be comfortable to raise because
sometime when you are in a team's
meeting the whole team is there. Um
someone may have an idea but may not be
feel comfortable to share in front of
everyone. But in a one- one you may you
can make your team member more
comfortable by sharing. what I what
would keep me um feel organized is that
I set out a task in order of importance
in in priorities that I need to to clear
for the morning and then for the
afternoon and then if things come up
then I would just keep adding them but
then I would make sure that I know which
one is more urgent and um yes as you
said around 3 we uh order coffee or
jessu right that's one thing and I feel
like the team keep is very excited for
for that on a daily basis So 3 p.m. is
his neck timing.
>> I need to come back.
>> I come back.
>> So as we mentioned before when you face
with a culture shock so how can we
achieve the that core value overcome the
culture shock you face with when you
join PBA.
I think for me um it's always back to
having an open mind to um respect the
differences the diversity whether it's
in age in um nationalities in thoughts
or just in personality in general and I
I feel like in PVA um people are
open-minded to respect and to appreciate
the differences among each other. So are
there any opportunity to work in your
team?
>> Definitely the opportunities are always
there right. So I think um for my team
the opportunities that I always give to
anyone especially young graduates is I
would learn what they want in their
career. So, as I said before, knowing
what you want,
>> it's a very exciting opportunities
because
you will do things that are uh sorry,
let me rephrase.
We have exciting opportunities uh in my
team we are uh we are working on like
very exciting use cases like uh AI use
cases that we need to you know do the
the risk assessment. So, we need to
ourselves to learn. So it's not
something like the static and keep
repeating. Since last year when I joined
I've been working for Pentia for one
year now there are so many things
happening so many initiatives. So I need
to prioritize because I cannot be
everywhere. My team cannot be everywhere
right? So I need to prioritize what are
the most important uh initiatives that
our team needs to be involved right. So
there are so many things to do. It's
like a big playground where I have so
many things to do.
supportive,
right?
Life insurance.
industry
very basic question for life life
insurance like persistency
support team they they are on board
quickly like mentoring coaching
training all these things
it's fun
it's always
[Music]
Disagreement
solution.
vocabulary.
Let's just agree.
[Music]
First of all,